So the text
says sa
end If you can
die changing the five
forces you will not get
into this
book
it's
long That's why it
took us 13
years He will say something like If you can
die with the five forces then you will get
into the good ones and
then the book is so long He does not say
what these 5
forces are That's why we have a
database
Here we are lucky that we have director
John here bdi is present mu can you please
stand up the Asian
heritage library by the way helped us many years
ago when we started the project and
they
seem to me if I'm not
mistaken include doctors 6 million pages
or more more than 6 million pages have
already been entered into the database and they are available
freely
online we save these pages then the
data and when they
already
use this
search engine that is this database of
about 15,000 books completed and it took us
35 years of hard work and
John helped us
with and when
the author says something Well, for example five
forces and you must die with the five forces and
then not say what these five forces are  I
go to this database and I pull them out
from there. We have an incredible military
program. The military program is very
powerful and therefore I can find. Maybe
I'll even
show you if I can share my
screen. I can
show you. Maybe next
time I
can examine all the pages in literally
half a second and I can cut out this
information about the five forces and
convey this work.
Our dear John Ready has done it for 35
years.
He's
such a
povoro. You understand about the World Cup. Well, give him a
donation.
He doesn't need to donate a million dollars while you're here.
They have about 5 dollars each.
Done.
10% of his work is already finished and he still needs to
continue working for years.
So, let's help him or something. Let's
gather him for a
team. So, the first of the five forces
is called the
first again.
What has John already donated to you?
Well, let's share like brothers. Yes, I'm
kidding. The first of the five forces is the white seed, the
power of the white
seed, bija in
Sanskrit is white seed, and I made
notes here. You can  honor them it
means take care of things before
you die
my
parents they both had
cancer dad dad
was such a big
man and quite
strong and he had cancer and he was
dying very slowly and he says oh he says I
will not die I refuse to die I
will fight ve and then he still
2 years 2 years it took to sort out
his financial
history 2 years where is all this money and in the
end we realized that there was nothing there at all
there was zero nothing at all
but there were a lot of problems for the
family because he did not prepare for
death and
mom I will
never forget
that I will forget we had four four
sons and she
called us said I want to show you something
she unbuttoned her shirt and said
look touch here there is a
bump and we were so ashamed a little
mom Why are you showing us your breasts she
says This is what will kill me I will die because of
this I want you to
know that this is cancer and I will have to die
Let's get ready and she
said straight out come on mom what to do how to
prepare for this Here you are  you care about
this because we will donate the money
to the church and distribute it to people
Degi she planned everything and then she
died and there was such a difference between
how dad and mom left
in our Buddhist tradition we
really encourage you we urge you to
prepare don't think
that Oh I'm not 71 yet like Gela I'm
30-40 years old listen we don't know who
will leave first we don't know Nobody really knows
someone just gets run over by a
car when he walks along the road to lamrim
and they don't come on the second day lamma
so prepare everything and you know you
will feel relief happiness I will tell
you so it is I do this I live So
I have everything ready grandpa will leave
and everything will be ready it's
actually relaxing And it's great It's
fun here you will get this And you will get
this much money and you will get my
blue
car let it be ti
Don't make your family suffer
your wife or your husband just everything
Prepare  be ready and do gko
Happy I u
can have my
car Can you with my
bank
mm
who will take your
backpack I haven't figured out yet who to give it to
KZA Repeat this
nome this
means the power of a good
habit here this
means in the right state of mind
practice Sometimes my teacher said
Every time you go before bed things to do and
then he says and also do meditation
on death if I die
Today I hope I can get to a
place where I can help people
and I hope I can help all living
beings When I die and like this
Prepare
yourself this is called a
habit this is past and
words get used to this become
used to this thought that you
will die don't be afraid don't avoid it on
the contrary take care of it If you
took care of this then you will not be
afraid And if not then you will have rakh
so take care of this initially
and then don't
die then you when the time comes to
die it is very comfortable it is not depressive that's
depressive this is when you
pretend that you won't die This is
really depressing If you
tell yourself Well, okay, here it is
Flesh and blood, it has to
go, just get used to this thought
Be prepared, take care of everything
I have everything ready, all the money is scheduled, what goes
where, who, about everything I'm sorry, I
work my
own job and that's why
If you don't die, well, that's
cool Everything is already
ready if you go to
Kyoto You
really are stupid if you don't have time to
pack your suitcases in 2
days, that is, crazy if sweat on the
same day is great You start to stress,
so pack your suitcases in advance
before you die,
do it while you're young, just
prepare and then you won't have to
worry about it then you're
ready and it's a good habit to talk
about it With your family, mom She loved
us very much
but she wasn't afraid to talk about it
until you feel comfortable Well, we said
Okay,
mom, of course, we loved her more than anything in the
world but we agreed with her ok,
let's get ready, we said ok,
Mommy, we have to be, we have to lead
myself too and then everything will be fine
third and this is a prayer after the bar wherever I
go I hope that I poison my
father that is, we are
projecting and we will understand This is the desire aspiration
I hope that after
I leave the Bardo I hope that I can
remember my motivation that I want to
help every living
being I can't leave take the
car with me I can't take the clothes with me
E I can't keep this skin a But
at least my motivation is that
I hope that I won't forget about it
so pray to this This is called projection projection
into the future what I'm talking
about you know
projecting
karma
fourth is the name of one of the
four forces it means the force of
destruction
in the four forces when we make a
confession it
means when we make a confession IS
will lead we
feel we regret what we did
and we decide to do it more
it
destroys means to
destroy this
that nyaki and also it sometimes means the
word rape to rape someone that is to
do something sharply
aggressive This
means confess make This
confession before you die it is
very
famous thing When you die when
you die before you die if
you can confess to all your
deeds I know everyone We have Greeks
that we hide and about which we
talk and it would be great before
you die If you can at least
tell someone about your most
terrible secret sins it would be
great if you could tell someone about it
this is very
powerful and this is
important before you go tell
someone when
pa I lived with him for some time there was nothing to
do it was already very late he was
dying very
slowly and we were watching
football he could not do anything anymore he was
sitting in a
chair and I remember how I pressed an
orange high he could not do anything
he was just dying slowly on
his right here m you must remember
someone close to you dies someone you love
then Help him make this
confession Help him
do I know that he killed people he
was a soldier during World
War II I know that he killed
people and that's why he didn't like to talk about it
never really talked about it
and I thought it would be
better if he said  share this
before he goes at least
tell someone about what he did we watched
football nothing more could
do to him orange
juice I'm such a dad can you
tell me about the war
a little tried to entice him
if you were in the same situation
again would you kill again he said No I
wouldn't do that again And I'm like Wow this is a
confession pure confession
he destroyed this karma basically
destroyed When you talk I
won't do it again I wouldn't do that This is this is
destruction I was so
glad about this I remember
Now he can purely
chi Even if you have to use
all sorts of methods people don't want to talk don't
want to be sincere
honest Be prepared so that even with the
most terrible deeds and sins before
you leave
just with your death If you
die tell him Share Don't be
shy you are dying so what
difference can they make only your name
will be afterwards so Tell about
your worst sins and cleanse
your heart and then you can leave
peacefully and this is very, very important if
you are run over by a car hit by a car and you
will bleed  blood and someone pisses you
okay I'm dying I'm not okay But by the way
I did such a terrible thing
just Tell someone
Tell it doesn't have to be something
some priest monk teacher just to
any person
Share I remember how a man
shared with a dog he was dying and he
told the dog his story about tam I killed someone
and the dog was like that
but at least he pulled it out of
himself clean it out and then you can
die peacefully and happily fifth
I'm here weak
flow
means an open
field and they
say they say in lajun in
Rome When you
die you don't
[music]
say there will be a place for me don't
say
So the biggest motivation I hope I
can take all these bad seeds from
everyone And go away and
die I will take all these seeds I will take
all these bad seeds out of this world so that there are
no remaining people is it
possible No of course you can't
do this I couldn't even one seed from you
Why are you doing such a Mole I hope I
can take these bad seeds when I
die but there was  Such an old Christian
tradition or maybe a Jewish
tradition, once a year in Jerusalem they
prayed, carried prayers,
and all the bad karma was, well, they
put it in a small colum and killed
it in the desert,
and from this lamb, I wish
everyone would say, well, you can put bad
karma in an animal and then kill
it. Of course, this is a terrible mistake. Well,
the idea itself is good. I can be
this sheep and give me all
your bad seeds. I pray. Of course, you
can't do that. It's just a
wish that you can take
all the bad karma. Give me your bad
karma. I'm dying. Give it to me and I will take
care of it.
This is such a good motivation. Sometimes you
can
practice
means
frequent practice of
bama on the fifth number
means you know the word
Ilina. What does measure mean and in this
context it
means the moment when you developed
lo, I don't know. And how to
understand there is
fishing, there is a definition of when
you have it, when you have it, when
you have this, you have a won when
here  You have this, you don't have it, it's
called I cut this out of the course
[music]
if you're
interested I took this
from there is that moment when you can
say that I have I developed a
good kind heart
this is the comment about how you recognize
If you have how you
understand
VKE
1996 approximately well it won't hurt to hear it again so I do
n't forget So let's
go I'll
go through these four points we'll go through
now
and there is
such a dividing line image
does this
mean
that it divides a lady and not a
lady and I highlighted the root text here in
cheese font
this
and the whole dharma comes down to one moment to
one idea in dharma comes down to one and
what is this
idea This
idea is such a pile of mountain of teachings dharma and
there is a
measure of how much how much
What quantity and this is 84,000
teachings taught 84 Cham or
mountains of
these teachings and they
received l is an
old verb that means All rivers
that flow into one
ocean All rivers flow into one
ocean All the teachings of Buddha that gave
Lord Buddha they flow into one ocean at
one point and
this
Can you stop your habit When
you care about yourself first of all the
teachings of the book all the
translations
everything comes to one point Can you
stop your habit your habit When
you initially care only about
yourself he
says that all rivers are in one ocean
that's a good word when we
draw a
mandala When you draw make a mandala
It is very it is very clear it is very
precise and you need to know geometry and this is
called tick these
lines we say these constructions
are used When you hold
this string like this
you have a straight even line and then you
do this with multi-colored powder
called what than what is this to
delimit your bad thought so this is
dharma if not then this is not dharma this
division to delimit a line for
dharma I took a lesson on dharma was it yes I do
n't
know
this dharma Tibetan or Sanskrit and
this will not help you get rid of your
negative emotions then this is not dharma you
go to a psychologist  Oh, it teaches you something
good that helps you mentally. Nata
level, then it's dharma, and it
seems to me I was nah, I didn't hear any gift.
And then I listened to my children at home, and I
heard from them that it
will teach you to be a
better person, to become a better person.
There are many teachings in the monastery, the teachings of Shi,
people become even
more proud, they are filled with pride, they
spend 25 years but they still don't
study. Someone tells you something and you
feel that the child is better. Here is a
gift. The
next image is the next
picture, and this is
such a gift. If you succeed,
repeat the
spiritual achievement or goal. So it
means signs, signs of
achievement, successful
practice,
gift, the highest
jewel, what will be the highest
sign that we are successful in our
practice?
Your negativity becomes less and less
every day, then you are successful. And if your
negative thoughts, emotions, and your
negative behavior become
less and less mixed, then then
dharma has its effect on
you, then it is dharma, and you are practicing a gift.
That is, if you become better
every day, then yes,
successful.  A practitioner is a gift if
you become a little bit
better, it won't
happen,
I'm just being honest with you, little by little, small,
small, progress is
enough. It's great when you're
trying to learn a language or you're trying to
learn some
skills in business, if every day you
become better and better. Don't
expect
that your envy that
you've been saving up for 20 years will immediately disappear. No, of course, it doesn't
work like that, you'll need much more, but
keep
getting a little better every day, and then
your bad habits won't evaporate like that.
In one day, in one year, I'll
tell you for sure, that's why even my
grandfathers are
better than I was last week, I'm
good for now.
No, better than last week. That's already good.
And then you're doing okay, a little
improvement every day, and you
become every year. That's it,
and then he says something very smart, he
says, a sign of
success is that you're getting a little better,
a little better every
year, then you've made progress.  and then he
says
it like that, it doesn't fly in the air, it flies.
In the sky, he flies. In the sky, he has an
army, yes. He flies in the sky, but he gets
irritated with people all the time, then he's a complete
failure. Yes, he says, "P, too, fly in the
sky, and what are you doing there?" Just
because you can fly in the sky doesn't
mean you're successful. Are
you less jealous every year? Are
you less irritated? Little
progress, you don't need to fly in the sky right away. There
were such discussions about
whether Geshi Michael was Geshi Michael Ari
or not. And someone said, "No, he's
not Ari, he can't fly in the sky,
but that's exactly what they're talking about
here. There's a
city where you can fly in the sky, where you can't
go underground, for example,
and he
says, "Even mice can do that, that does
n't mean anything."
Can you fly out or
walk through a stone? That's not true
siha. But iha is that. Do you
feel less jealousy compared to
last year? Do you have fewer desires
compared to last year?  then this is
progress and just that you are there through nku
prol even sh
and then he
says There are also such siki that
can walk on
water or go under a river, for example, through a
river on
water, go to the other
side, but he says Yes, even a fish can
do this, even a fish is capable of
[music]
such a thing and a fish can walk on water, swim
on water, think of an achievement But if
you can control your
competitiveness in business, then
you have real progress then
when you are a Saint and only
because you can fly in the sky, walk on
water, go through walls, think of it,
birds fly, mice run, fish can walk
on
water,
achievement What do we have there with
time until
the question Yes In 15 minutes there will be
[music]
questions scales remember before we weighed
vegetables in the markets,
fruits and he says the practice of la jong
is like a
scale You can use your
practice of lo jong to
measure your success and - these are scales on
which we can measure our success of
karma to weigh it
means a fingerprint a fingerprint
in the teachings a gift
means
success and in your practice it is called as
an imprint
from ru or no and this
Otto gift is whether your egoism has become less has it become
whether your egoism has decreased has it decreased is
your egoism decreasing This is a
sign of
success a handprint
It's like fingerprints
for example at a
crime scene someone was a good
person I saw a
sign what sign I'm not like last
year for example this will be a recognition of your
success a handprint or footprint of
success next the next
picture this is exactly the scales
we talked about Scales of
Justice ray in Mom's garden at home they died
Then two
friends arrived and they came to my cafe and they
planted two trees and they look they
grow just like
crazy I even sold peaches
and
great job guys I don't know what to do with the
ground than
dobri this is about
relationships Leave one or
DH witnesses
judge unusual word mu 000 years
some words they are over ssia years and
therefore
difficult means witness or
judge he says sa main judge who is this so did
I mix up the
pictures burn there is a
witness Pony if there are two witnesses of
your mental state state of
mind which of them  More important are you or
other
people who know your state of mind better than
anyone else. We try to look better for
others. We don't care how we look.
Our minds are already dirty with stains. We live with
it and that's normal, but we want to
pretend in front of other people. Shila
wants to look so holy in her
teachings and then goes home and
watches Netflix all night. Kato soap operas, Korean
soap operas, look very good in
public. There's this in the Ancient Texts.
Jon says who you want to impress.
Who you should
impress is the audience that
comes to your teaching or yourself
alone. What's more important, of course, is
you alone who knows who you really are,
so don't try to pretend to be
other people. We try to look
better in front of others and we don't care how much
dirt there is inside us, but
we need it on the contrary.
There are many famous teachers
who don't bathe there for weeks, for
example, so
that people
don't... They are very, very clean for themselves. He  and
clean And for others they don't look
clean Well, and they Well, they are happy,
so don't try to look
good in the eyes of others, try
to look good in the eyes of yourself in your
heart You must look at your
heart and say This is a beautiful thing, this is
beautiful, so that oh, how much
makeup I did for myself there and it's expensive too
Guys, don't go to the hospital in the iconostasis, you won't fly out of there,
you won't leave without
spending hundreds of
dollars, it's expensive, so it's much
cheaper to just do some makeup and
decorate for yourself You need to be beautiful
inside and then the appearance may get
better, maybe not, but Be
beautiful first of all, you are your own
judge of your beauty, no one else
decides whether you are beautiful or
not It's
clear If you look inside yourself
You really should feel
beautiful, feel beautiful, but
external beauty It's hard to maintain,
it only lasts a few years,
then you have to put on more makeup, a
whole ton of plaster on yourself
To
look, take care of your inner
state Be sexy inside and
inside out Well, big deal
Everything will
fall apart anyway, other people judge
us  With you We have a
habit We present ourselves as different
as if we are better in front of other
[music]
people Sometimes I'm just
kidding Like Ola idiot
Yeah, relax And I don't need to
look like
someone smart Letter to the king Nagar
what were those two famous
letters
He
says it's such a big topic in
India because once a
year it ripens I was there during that season there are
10 dollars a whole bag then in the second
week there are already
dollars then they
try to
sell dollars they grow very high and
then it's hard to judge what's inside whether it's a
good
mango or not And you ask a child to climb in
and see if it's
good or not and there is a famous
example whether a person is
really good or not we don't know
People like Mango look very good but
inside the floor is just complete crap or
vice versa it looks
bad very beautiful that's
why people like Mango that's why I'm tired of
judging these mangos Who knows someone is
very sweet such a sweet appearance And
what's going on inside is unclear and he
says we don't
know
what it is
hiding in the
mouth Maybe it
means
and he
says rat  They hide in their
holes. We can't. We can't judge a
person by their
appearance. Sometimes there's a person who's
really evil inside, but we think,
Well,
he's
cruel
inside, and he gives
possible options. What are
the options called? Man seems good, a good fruit
on top, but inside, or vice versa, it looks
possible.
Ria is
good inside, good inside, bad outside,
bad
inside, and sometimes Mango seems to be
inside. And from the street, it looks like
he is, so a person can also look
so evil, but he has a big. A kind
heart
inside, looks bad. Mango on the outside,
but
good,
what does that
mean?
Repeat, repeat.
I'm just trying to wake you up
so you don't fall asleep here.
This is Arma
Ko, and this is such a
virtuous
mind. We say judgment and
foresight. Lord, shame and
foresight. Every time you
do good, the
first thing that happens is that
you're really
worried about Tom. There
won't
be an audience.
Of course, this is
called
goodness,
what will it be?
People mean
that you have the opportunity
to see no one
there, no one will even recognize you. If you
watched this, and you
say to yourself, I don't want to
be,
I don't want people to see this. This is such a thing.  A
healthy way is healthy I want
people to see a bad person
look
bad it is more powerful
meaning But at home by myself when no
one sees me
myself and I don't want to be look bad
Even in my room when
I'm here he
says We want to be clean on the outside and
clean on the
inside good Mango we want to be
good
Percy what can you see from the street BC
if they earn themselves a bad
reputation in
the world
they don't usually think about it It's not about the
World Cup they should
what are you called if someone trolls
them they don't waste time to protect
they are like oh well it doesn't matter what
people say
about me in a good way oh well people
say about
me a good
person they just just act like a
good
person their main interest is
not to look like a good
person but to be a good person the main
effort they make is to be a good person on the
inside
and the main thing of their efforts is not to
look like good Although they care about it they
must
care we don't want people to think
that we are bad people and therefore a good
person also needs to think about
it But the most important thing is to be
good on the inside It doesn't matter What people think about
you then  what do you look like
If you waste your
time trying to defend yourself in
front of all sorts of trolls or, on
the contrary, fight your mental
screaming and negative emotions I think it's
better to work on your mental training and the
trolls will
disappear on their own This is my philosophy I don't want to
waste my time trying to
prove to someone that I'm a good person I
think I just focus on
being a really good
person
and sooner or later the internet will
pick up this
flow the next picture is
rejoice Tim when I should already
do and I already
should So tomorrow
Tomorrow we'll do it I think it's time
yes let's stop at this place Yes
this is a great place let's stop
here next
advice
godfather is to enjoy have
fun for me many di who are
engaged
If you know what happens after
you die
where ch We had a good
time said la need to go to the hotel straight
to the airport maybe someone is there with
flowers I said no I'll go now and
just have a very tasty dinner I just
stole everyone We live in mke we don't have good
restaurants
there If you end up in Kyoto  then
definitely of course I'll go to a good
restaurant have fun Life is
short If you practice really
good Rome You should have
fun I don't mean go
gamble in a casino or
drink No of course I'm not talking about that
relax and have fun
life is so
short
sms s
I understand have fun ra If
you are a good Buddhist then you should
always be in a good mood as it seems to me
and just have fun such
pure good
pleasure
questions I
understand
when there is no beginning no
end we taught at level
12 that if there is no seed there is no result then
that the system and the result exist at the same
time I exist in the present time and
level Wow We are
also very
fast
I am the ideal me or that which I which
I dream about it already exists Then why is this
What kind of high-speed point
exactly the same learned at the seventh
level If everything that
happens has emptiness This
means that emptiness it also has
pu also
has
that principle it is like
Gravity about it relates to everything in this way in fact
understand the principle of sem
that it is also pu and this is my main
question Thank you
very much
God It seems to me that the translators  I'm
just having a heart
attack right now. This is a good question.
I just finished the
book. I've been working on it for several
years. I've been working on the book. It's a really
fascinating process. He
translated poems
into proof.
He translated this
book and in this book,
Nana, he puts a lot of emphasis on it.
He says, "
If you really understand the cause,
then this is emptiness, but technically, this is
completely wrong, and there's a big
argument and debate about this.
NHF, and
this is dependent origination, and this
emptiness is itself also emptiness, and this is not true.
This is not true. Emptiness cannot
change, but the cause must
change in order to lead to the result or
consequence, and it seems that he is saying
something contradictory, and then Jen
Capa, 1200 years later, he says the same thing.
He says the greatest thing about the World Cup that
Buddhists taught was dependent origination because
it is emptiness, and this is somehow confusing.
I'll repeat, I'll repeat
again, the mental seed creates yours, and it
changes every time the seed
changes.  It is
destroyed when the seed turns into a
tree,
and they change me in order to
bring it there will be no result
if the seed is still there, then a tree cannot, and if it is
already a tree, then the seed cannot, the seed must
be destroyed before a
tree can appear. And this is always the case, then emptiness is
not what I will give you now. An example of sweat.
You have a mouse in the kitchen, a
mouse, mice. Well, I sometimes have one, though,
but I don’t have one, for example, do you have
mice in the
kitchen? I say no. Have you ever caught a
mouse? I have this Mongolian
trap. It’s
cool. There are no
springs there. There are two, three, three, three
sticks. You can catch any mouse. It
doesn’t matter how smart and savvy it is. The
Mongolian gave it to me. So, if there is a mouse in
your kitchen and you removed the mouse from the kitchen,
then is there a mouse in your kitchen? Is there
emptiness?
Mouse in your kitchen? If there is no muscle mass in your
kitchen, yes, there is. Let’s see. When a mouse
runs and everything is crap everywhere, then
you have a mouse. You caught this mouse and
took it out.  Then you created, did
you then have such a thing in the kitchen
that is called the absence of a mouse in the
kitchen? The absence of a mouse in the kitchen
changes, it cannot change.
Why?
Can you have half a mouse in the
kitchen or is the mouse in the kitchen or not?
There are no other
options when the mouse returns back to the
kitchen. Where does this emptiness disappear? We
just disappear. It does not become smaller
when the mouse's nose gets there.
But
when the whole mouse is there, then in the absence of a mouse,
it is considered, but when the mouse's nose is there, but I don't
know. If the mouse is still in the kitchen or
not, that is, either it is there or it is not there.
We cannot say that half a mouse
in the kitchen is not a
clog. It can exit
existence, but it cannot change. There is a
mouse in the kitchen or the absence of a mouse in the
kitchen. The
absence of a mouse in the kitchen can disappear
when the whole mouse appears in the kitchen,
but it does not become bigger or smaller.
You cannot say that I have 50% of the
absence of a mouse in the kitchen. You cannot say that
either it is in your kitchen or it is not there. In
the kitchen,
therefore, the absence of a mouse cannot
change. It cannot be half a mouse,
it does not work like that. Oh, I have
the absence of not half a mouse in the kitchen here, there is no
This is not true, therefore emptiness
cannot change, but absence
cannot either. It can either appear
or disappear, but it cannot change. I
see. This is the
difference between a seed and a
result. The seed disappears, disappears, and the
result does not stop. The result grows, grows, grows,
the tree appears, but
absence does not change. I apologize.
Absence does not change,
but interdependence changes. Why does Nana
then
say that
emptiness and dependent origination are the same thing? Because this is
not true. One of them
never changes, the other changes all the time.
Then why does she say something that is not
true? I
will tell you to read the next book when
it comes out. It is a very cool
book. In
Buddhism, there are two divisions. We call it
Hinayana and Mahayana. The lower
path is the higher path. Sometimes Hinayana
is called Rovada, which means the True
Path. If you call it
Hinayana, you call it
Rovada, this is
normal. There is a lower path and a higher
path. Two types of Buddhism. People
say that Lord
Buddha, at the first turning of the
wheels of
teaching, the first period when he taught in
this world, he taught
Hiya, then  700 years
ago and he
taught
this who doesn't talk about ba ba
mentioned Once And in general, don't
say anything, he's so cool
about not starting any Mahayana, it's always been
Mahayana, it's always
been
clear This is so
cool I didn't start anything here at all during the World Cup,
I did all this about emptiness,
you just didn't understand it, he
talked about Mahayana all the time And you guys just didn't
understand dependent origination is
emptiness, the first teaching of Buddha is
interdependence, the greatest, the greatest,
then later Nagarjuna begins to talk
about emptiness and Nagarjuna
says in six verses he says that these
people are quinones, guys, you didn't understand anything at all
that Buddha taught emptiness from the very
first day of the very first minute He didn't
talk about Hina Maha, this is stupid, he always
taught Mahayana, this is Hinayana But he doesn't It's
clear his teaching of interdependence is the
teaching of emptiness of the
CR, he didn't say just changing
Venya, in fact, interdependent pros is
emptiness If you think that  it's
different
If you think that some guy
started teaching by waving, you're wrong. There
was talk about emptiness all the time. You just
didn't understand
him. Then
he uses all these ancient
sources to
prove
this. I think you
read it. But your question was very,
very beautiful. By
the way, we did one thing in
this book. I want to brag that
we went through the whole book, 60
verses.
Then we went to the
bottom database. And we checked how these ideas. How many
of these ideas survived? And how many didn't
survive? And it's interesting. Some of the
greatest
ideas are not
you.
Can you prove it? Using the Dan database,
statistically, we simply
put the percentage on All ideas and got
these statistics. The number of ideas on Guard is
interesting. Can you show
statistically that the basis of statistical
data is 1800 years old. Some ideas
that he wanted to teach simply disappeared.
Well, I don't know. It was bad luck or something like that
happens in monasteries.
Maybe the teacher there got sick and he
simply didn't convey this idea and the
students didn't get it and then they didn't.
passed this on to their students and the idea
gradually disappears and you can show
which ideas disappear and this is great It's
interesting it seems that what he wanted to
happen did not happen because no
one ever applied them because no
one understood them and it can be proven
that some of them Eh Hov no one understood for
2000 years because they were never
applied and they
disappeared they are not even in the database it can be
proven I
thought maybe he knew about
this because at the very end I will
need to
do all this analysis and I'm like
Wait I think Nagarjuna is
fooling us I think he wants us to
figure this out ourselves and he hopes that we will
teach these ideas and bring them back we will return them back so
he and in fact maybe
he can that these are going on
Revival of
ideas after John
b I liked this I really you
can read about it when the book
I think Rose will help us so that it will
come out quickly everything we all
when I need to be
there no no no need additional we have done a lot today with
you you are great it's hard to
listen to this I don't know You can't imagine how much
I suffered in monasteries when teachers are like
that
I'd even get tired of it.
I always made
a promise to myself: When I become a geshi and start
teaching, I will also mock the students in the same way.